Now,
we are back in Mercado,
and we're going to create the recipe.
For requesting the data.
Of
We're back in Ricato.
Now,
we saw the data table here.
Now we're going to take advantage of that data table.
We want to create the first API,
which is the pending requests.
We want to show the manager all the requests that are pending.
So we're going to get the data.
We'll fetch it from this data table.
So we're gonna create.
A recipe.
And it's going to be called
pending.
Requests
And we're going to build an
API endpoint
and start building.
And since this is a request,
we're going to send a response.
So,
we can go to the response.
And it's going to be standard response.
And here we can go ahead and select
the correct response back that we're going to give
when
the API is called.
So,
we'll just do the 200,
though you can do others.
You can add additional ones and you'll see this
in our third step where this shows up.
And now,
here,
we're going to use JSON.
And I have copied
onto the clipboard.
That request that we talked about
earlier.
So,
remember,
we need an array.
And the workcao tool will use this example.
And then we'll
generate the schema for us so we don't have to worry.
And I'll go ahead and save this data.
Now,
what we want to do,
because this is for pending,
we are going to take a look at
filtering the data from the data table.
So,
it's like data table.
we're going to filter the Wikcado data,
so we need to search the records.
So,
we'll click on search.
And we need to select the correct data table.
So this is our computer request approval data
table that we're going to be searching.
And next,
we'll need to create a filter
to filter
which
items,
and we're going to filter the status.
And
the status equals what equals pending.
And then we can add a few more things here,
we'll just uh sort by the last modified time.
Descending,
and we're going to add one more field here,
just so that
the data gets displayed,
uh,
sent correctly.
Um
Here we're going to select.
Field name to value,
otherwise we get the hash values,
which is not what we want.
OK.
And then the last piece now.
So now that we've filtered the results,
we got all the pending data,
we haven't actually sent back the response
to
the API,
the API request.
So,
now,
let's do the 3rd step.
And add that.
So we're going to use the
API platform by Workato.
We're going to respond to an API request.
And here,
remember I mentioned that could be multiple responses.
We only configured the 200 response.
I'll click on OK.
And then it has all the fields.
Now I'm going to select all.
We can see here request is showing as
the icon as an array,
which is what we wanted.
So,
I'll select all and apply the changes.
And now we're going to select the list here.
And we're going to go to records
and we'll fill in the rest.
The data table here very simply.
And now we can click on the save button on the top here.
And that will uh complete.
The recipe
that we needed.
Now,
there's more things
that need to be completed,
but let's just go back here to the project.
We have our data table
and we have created the API pending request.